NYSUT President's Office Files. 6174/001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- University/Urban Schools National Task Force Conference, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  Ritz Carlton, Buckhead, Atlanta, GA. Agenda, 11/8-11/9/91; biographies of presenters; printed report, "Multiple Choices: Reforming Student Testing in New York State: A Report of the NYSUT Task Force on Student Assessment," January 1991; printed executive summary, "National Education Goals Report: Building a Nation of Learners," 1991; printed booklet, "America 2000: An Education Strategy," by U.S. Department of Education, 1991 (revised); National Alliance of Business printed executive summary, "Corporate Action Agenda: The Business of Improving Public Education," n.d.; National Alliance of Business policy statement, "A National Assessment System," n.d.; publications list for national education goal panel, "Next Steps Toward Measuring National and State Progress," November 8, 1991; routine correspondence; newspaper clippings
- Vaughn, Jacqueline, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  Memorial program, newspaper clippings, and biographical materials re Vaughn, president of Chicago Teachers Union
- Vocational Education, see NYS Advisory Council on Vocational Education, 1990
- VOTE/COPE (Committee on Political Action, NYSUT) Meeting, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  December 1, 1995. Minutes, financial reports, and expenditure authorizations for February 7, 1995, meeting; agenda for December 1, 1995, meeting
- VOTE/COPE Meeting, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  February 4, 1995. Minutes, financial reports, and expenditure authorizations for February 4, 1995, and August 9, 1994, meeting
- VOTE/COPE Meeting, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  August 9, 1994. Agenda and expenditure authorizations; list of expenditures
- VOTE/COPE Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  8/20/93. Agenda and expenditure authorizations; minutes
- VOTE/COPE Meeting, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  June 29, 1993. Agenda and expenditure authorizations; minutes
- VOTE/COPE Meeting, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  August 12, 1992. Agenda and expenditure authorizations; minutes
- VOTE/COPE Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  July 27, 1992. Agenda and expenditure authorizations; minutes
- VOTE/COPE Meeting, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  January 27, 1987. Agenda and expenditure authorizations; minutes
- VOTE/COPE: Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  Letter to Tom Hobart from Angela Symula (Fredonia Teachers' Association), 3/3/93; correspondence between Tom Hobart and Aaron Seligman, treasurer, Nassau Community College Federation of Teachers, 2/1993-10/1993; letter from Rick Crandell, 2/5/95
- VOTE/COPE: Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  Memos re purchase of tickets to the Democratic and Republican state fundraisers, May-June 1987; routine courtesy correspondence
- VOTE/COPE: Lobbying, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  New York Times clipping mentioning NYSUT as biggest spender on lobbying in the state
- Wappingers Congress of Teachers, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  Correspondence from WCT president Ron Warman re "taxpayer revolt" by Dione Goldin, with attached leaflets, June 9; re staffing issues at NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office; NY Times clipping
- Warman, Ron, see Wappingers Congress of Teachers
- Youth Employment and Training Advisory Council (NYS Department of Labor), 1989 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  NYS Department of Labor Report, "Youth Programs in NYS," December 1989; Youth Employment and Training Advisory Council Executive Committee Report; program committee report; summary of full council meeting, October 3, 1989, with cover letter to NYSUT president Hobart; agenda of January 17, 1990, meeting; draft Survey of State Agencies Relative to Youth Employment Policy Goals, March 31, 1989
- Youth Employment and Training Advisory Council, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  Correspondence with Hobart from NYS Department of Labor Commissioner Thomas Hartnett re new advisory council, November 1988; agenda for November 10, 1988, meeting; membership list; cost reimbursement criteria for members; proposed 12-month calendar; proposed mission statement; related information; New York State Job Training Partnership Council "Statement of Policy on Youth Employment Investment," March 1988
- Series Presidents Files: NYSUT Subseries
  See also NYSUT History Project Interview; see also President's Perspective.
  - NYSUT Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on JTPC Study Committee, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    May 10, 1991. Albany Regional Office Conference Room
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    June 22, 1993. Agenda; list of Administrative Committee meetings for 1993-94; program for NYSUT Board of Directors meeting, June 29-30; tentative schedule for vacation shutdown
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    June 8, 1993. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    May 25, 1993. Agenda; list of local presidents, participation in Local Presidents' Conference
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    April 20, 1993. Agenda; materials re Local Presidents' Conference, comparison of Representative Assembly participation for 1989, 1992, 1993
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    March 30, 1993. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    February 23, 1993. Agenda; proposed constitutional amendments; newspaper clippings
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    February 2, 1993. Agenda; newspaper clipping
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    January 5, 1993. Agenda; text of legal opinion and order by Supreme Court Appellate Division, Third Judicial Department, Louis Grumet (individually and as executive director of NYS School Boards Association, In.) v. Board of Education of the Kiryas Joel Village School District, September 15, 1992; list of EMS Field Services Team Leader appointments by the NYS Education Department
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    December 8, 1992. Agenda; newspaper clippings
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    November 24, 1992. Agenda; list of proposed changes to Commissioner's Regulations Part 83: Good Moral Character for teacher certification; related materials; description of NYSUT school restructuring project training
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 54)
    October 27, 1992. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    October 14, 1992. Agenda; publication schedule for New York Teacher
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    September 9, 1992. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    June 30, 1992. Agenda; program for Presidents Conference on Endorsements
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 58)
    May 5, 1992. Agenda; proposed meeting schedule for NYSUT Executive Committee, Board of Directors, and Administrative Committee, 1992-93
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 59)
    April 21, 1992. Agenda; newspaper clippings
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 60)
    April 7, 1992. Agenda; list of Hotel, Motel & Restaurant Employees & Bartenders Union Local 471 hotels and restaurants, rev. March 16, 1992; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    March 5, 1992. Agenda; Representative Assembly program; AFL-CIO boycott flyer
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 62)
    February 19, 1992. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 63)
    February 4, 1992. Agenda; questionnaire for presidents of elementary and secondary teacher locals 1991-92 re issues including academic freedom, substance abuse, technology, salaries
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 64)
    January 22, 1992. Agenda; media report; press release, "Teachers Launch Statewide Campaign Against School Aid Cuts," January 20, 1992; newspaper clippings
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 65)
    January 7, 1992. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 66)
    December 17, 1991. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 67)
    December 6, 1991. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 68)
    November 21, 1991. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 69)
    November 5, 1991. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 70)
    October 25, 1991. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 71)
    October 8, 1991. Agenda; memo re emergency office closure procedures
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 72)
    September 11, 1991. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 73)
    June 17, 1991. Agenda; tentative schedule for vacation shutdown
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 74)
    June 4, 1991. Agenda; newspaper clipping
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 75)
    April 24, 1991. Agenda; Teacher Retirement Incentive Act of 1991 walk- through memorandum; memo to Administrative Committee re assignment of Representative Assembly Resolutions and Special Orders of Business for Implementation, April 24, 1991
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 76)
    April 9, 1991. Memo re conference supplies and promotional items, February 2
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 77)
    March 12, 1991. Agenda; program of annual Representative Assembly to be held March 21-24, 1991; list of speakers
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 78)
    February 26, 1991. Agenda; memo re recycling program
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 79)
    January 3, 1991. Agenda
  - NYSUT Administrative Committee Meeting, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 80)
    December 18, 1990. Agenda; memo re impact of decision by U.S District Court for the Southern District of New York on collective bargaining, December 11
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 81)
    12/1-12/2/95. Outline and text of president's report; report of second vice president Walter E. Dunn, Jr.; report of secretary-treasurer Fred Nauman; NYSUT Executive Committee minutes of November 16 and December 1, 1995, meetings; report on the Jewish Labor Committee trip to Israel for trade union study tour, November 29; testimony of Alan Lubin, Executive Vice President, NYSUT, to the Standing Committee on Education, Local Governments, Real Property Taxation and Ways & Means, Legislative Commission on Government Administration, November 29; memo re proposed dues for 1996-97 and 1997-98; revised action items of Representative Assembly; memo from first vice president Antonia Cortese re shared decision-making biennial review, November 27; Empire State Survey report, "Students at Risk: New Yorkers on Education," project of Empire Foundation and Lehrman Institute, July 6-24; report of Committee to Review Responsibilities of Board Members; newsletters: The Chalk Board (for current and retired NYSUT employees), fall 1995; The Retiree Organizer (for NYSUT retiree leaders), November 1995; NYS AFL-CIO Unity, October 1995
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 82)
    12/3-12/4/93. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; report of second vice president; Executive Committee minutes of December 3 meeting; confidential memo re revaluation of NYSUT policy providing legal representation in sexual misconduct cases, arising from teacher convicted of child molestation, with attached newspaper clipping, December 2; draft of VOTE/COPE policy re local political activities, December 1; outline of tentative agreement for Rochester Teachers Association; Regents 1994-95 Proposal on State Aid to Schools; draft certified audit for NYSUT and NYSUT Building Corporation, December 3; minutes of NYSUT Building Corporation Board of Directors meeting of November 10; materials re Representative Assembly (campaign and election procedures, agenda); "To Russia with Workshops 1993," trip report by Alan B. Lubin; revision to 1976 policy re interest-free strike loans; proposed NYSUT policy on pre-K and kindergarten, November 23; Q&A sheet re NYSUT long-term care plan, and workbook; August 31, 1993, memo from Computer Committee re microcomputers, November 30
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 83)
    6/28-6/29/93. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; memo re 1993-94 school budget defeats by district and comparison with previous year, June 23; final report, NYSUT 1993 Pre- and Post- Advertising Campaign Survey re effectiveness of "limit class size" television ad message, June 23, 1993, compiled by Fact Finders, Delmar, NY; report on attendance at 1993 NYSUT Representative Assembly; NYSUT proposal, Personal Income Tax Reform, June 1993; NYSUT legislative memos; NY Times clipping
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 84)
    4/29/93. Agenda; proposed policy on inclusion, opposing total mainstreaming of students with disabilities; resolution in support of tobacco-free schools; special report, "Conflict in the Classroom: Drawing the Line on Bad Behavior" and press release, April 29; survey of presidents of elementary and secondary teacher locals 1992-93; newspaper clippings
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 85)
    2/26-2/27/93. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; report of second vice president; report of secretary-treasurer; draft policy on inclusion, opposing total mainstreaming of students with disabilities; NYSUT response to the Curriculum and Assessment Council Interim Report; resolution re Legal Defense Reimbursement Fund; proposed changes in legal representation policy in "good moral character" proceedings; amendments to tax sheltered savings and investment plan for Professional Staff Association and Communication Workers of America local 1141; materials for Representative Assembly; proposed constitutional amendments; confidential memo re interviews of candidates for Board of Regents, February 26; standard comparison on school aid estimates, 1992-93; newsletters
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 86)
    12/4-12/5/92. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; report of second vice president; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; August 31, 1992, NYSUT certified audit, December 4; 1992 Statewide Focus Groups: Public Attitudes Toward Education, complied by Fact Finders, Delmar, NY, December 4; materials for Representative Assembly; Commissioner's Regulations Part 83: Good Moral Character; confidential report of the NYS PTA 95th Annual Convention; political action committee nominations
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 87)
    9/25-9/26/92. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; report of second vice president; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; letter to Commissioner Sobol from NYS School Boards Association urging strengthening of proposed amendment to Commissioner's Regulations Part 83: Good Moral Character, that conviction for a felony constitutes conclusive presumption of lack of same, May 15; text of proposed amendment, submitted to Board of Regents, September 2; NYSUT memo opposing change, September 18; resolutions terminating legal service plan; year-end report by NYSUT Division of Research & Educational Services re participation of locals and members in selected activities
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 88)
    7/28-7/29/92. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; Executive Committee minutes of June 11 meeting; memo from Toni Cortese with information re tracking and detracking, July 28; materials for Representative Assembly; information bulleting re teacher salaries, 1991-92; report, "Standards: A Vision for Learning," Council for Basic Education, winter 1991; equipment budget; NYSUT Building Corporation minutes of annual membership meeting, June 24, 1991, and Board of Directors meeting, June 11, 1992; letter from NYS Public Employment Relations Board deputy chairman and counsel John M. Crotty to Louis Grumet, executive director of the NYS School Boards Association, objecting to association's use of a paper by Crotty to lobby Commissioner Sobol re modification of regulation re shared decision-making, July 24; letter from Daniel Walsh, president, Business Council of New York State, to Carlos Carballada, chancellor, NYS Board of Regents, defending Career Pathways Task Force recommendations, July 9, 1992; letter from Walsh to Regent Laura Chodos arguing that dropout rates and similar measurements are inadequate to assessing school accountability, July 10; letter to Commissioner Sobol from SUNY chancellor D. Bruce Johnstone commenting on Education that Works recommendations of Career Pathways Task Force (Governor's Task Force on Creating Career Pathways for New York State Youth), July 14, 1992; address of Albert Shanker to the 1992 Democratic National Convention
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 89)
    3/22/92. Agenda; minutes of March 19 meeting; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of March 19; minutes of Ad Hoc Committee on Leadership Development, March 10; affiliation requests
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 90)
    2/7-2/8/92. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; Executive Committee minutes of January 30; memo from Toni Cortese re proposed NYSUT policy to conform to OSHA standards on bloodborne pathogens (HIV and others), February 4; membership analysis as of December 31, 1991, and June 30, 1991; memo from Hobart summarizing Career Pathways recommendations, soliciting input, February 6; application for 1992 Walt Disney Company American Teacher Awards; ad and photo of billboard opposing cuts in state education; final report of 1991 Education Opinion Survey, complied by Fact Finders, Delmar, NY, November 12, 1991; summary of recent legal decisions (Hoerger vs Great Neck Board of Education, Kiyas Joel Village School District, R.E.F.I.T. School Funding, Lag Payroll), February 7
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Dinner/Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 91)
    12/6/91. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; report of second vice president; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; Executive Committee minutes of December 6 and November 7; Governor's Proposed 1991-92 Mid-Year School Aid Budget Cuts (net reductions per district); trustee indemnity agreement; materials for Representative Assembly; legislative bulletins
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 92)
    9/13-9/14/91. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; Executive Committee minutes of September 13; monthly report by NYSUT Division of Research and Education Services, September 1992; recommendations of the NYSUT Ad Hoc Task Force on Elementary Education; text of proposed amendment to Commissioner's Regulations re shared decision-making, with attached memo to Board of Regents outlining purpose of change, August 30; position paper by NYSUT, "Shared Decision-Making and the New Compact for Learning"; memo recommending establishment of Retiree Advisory Committee, September 13; report and recommendations of Task Force on Retiree Structure, September 13; trustee indemnity agreements; map or NYS Election Districts (for NYSUT), with photos of NYSUT Board of Directors on reverse; NYSUT information bulletin re teachers' salaries 1990-91; report, "Retrenchment in the Northeast: Origins, Duration, Policy Options," prepared for American Federation of Teachers, re federal spending cuts, downturn of economy, June 19
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 93)
    6/24/91. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; Executive Committee minutes of June 6; NYSUT Building Corporation minutes of annual membership meeting, June 25, 1990, and Board of Directors meeting, December 7, 1990, March 21, 1991, and June 6, 1991; Report to the Board of Regents of the Social Studies Syllabus Review and Development Committee, June 13
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 94)
    February 8-9, 1991. Agenda; outline and text of president's report; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; Executive Committee minutes of February 8, 1991; monthly report by NYSUT Division of Research and Education Services, February 1991; memorandum opinion from NYSUT general counsel James R. Sandner re Tier I retirement benefits for teachers who, prior to 1965, were required to take unpaid leaves of absence or resign for maternity/child rearing, February 6; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson to local presidents re lobbying effort against state budget cuts to education, February 4; sample ads; report by the NYSUT Task Force on Student Assessment: "Multiple Choices: Reforming Student Testing in New York State," January 1991, and memo from Hobart to AFT Executive Council, January 28
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    December 7-8, 1990. Agenda; minutes of September 14-15 meeting; outline and text of president's report; financial statements of secretary-treasurer and year-end audit; NYSUT Constitution, March 1990; proposed amendments; proposed dues recommendations; draft report by the NYSUT Task Force on Student Assessment, December 1990; affiliation requests; letter from New York Post announcing introduction of new weekly "labor page," with attached first edition for review; proposed resolutions for NYSUT conventions
  - NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    December 8-9, 1989. Agenda; text of president's report; financial statements of secretary-treasurer; NYSUT Constitution, as amended through 1988 Representative Assembly; revised pension formula; recommendations of Committee on Referred Resolutions, December 1; materials for Representative Assembly; "Focus on Retirement Q&A for '89"
  - NYSUT Board Committee on Responsibilities for Board Members, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    November 28, 1995. Agenda; outline of board, at- large, and election district members' responsibilities
  - NYSUT Board Committee on Internal Organization, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    August 10, 1994. Sheraton Inn. Agendas for meetings of June 9, May 9, April 14, February 11, January 13, 1994, December 3, November 10, September 10, June 9, April 29, February 26, January 12, 1993; agendas, AFT Executive Council 1993-94; agendas, NYSUT Board of Directors meetings, 1993-94
  - NYSUT Budget, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - NYSUT Budgets: Presidents Office (Hobart), 1990-1991 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    8/1990-12/1991. Monthly management financial reports (spreadsheets)
  - NYSUT Budgets: Presidents Office (Hobart), 1989-1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    8/1989-7/1990
  - NYSUT Budgets: Presidents Office (Hobart), 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    12/1987-7/1989
  - NYSUT Employees Retirement, see NYSUT Retirement
  - NYSUT Executive Committee Meeting, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 9)